Finding Aid for the Bound Manuscripts Collection LSC.0170
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Bound Manuscripts
  - Marchmont, A.C.V. Beauchamp Vernon: a Sketch (England, ). **Unpublished manuscript, with seven original watercolour and sepia tone illustrations., 1858; 170/557; Manuscript, 300pp.
  - Catholic Church. Liturgy and ritual. Confessional manual (S. France s. XIII med.)., 170/558; Parchment. **One quire. In Latin and Provencal.
  - Priuli, Francesco. Rifugio dei Miseri (Italy s. XV²)., 170/559; Manuscript, on paper. 59 leaves.
  - George of Trebizond. Expositio in orationem M. Tullii Ciceronis pro Q. Ligario (Italy s. XV)., 170/560
  - Pazzi, Antonio de; Torquato Tasso. Canzone, stanze (Italy s. XVI²)., 170/561; One quire of 8 leaves.
  - Borrow, George Henry (1803-1881). Lavengro (England, )., 1851; 1872; 170/562; Page Proofs, with manuscript note giving an account of the corrected page proofs.
  - Vacant., 170/563
  - Leighton, John (1822-1912). Alphabet Drawings (England s.a.). **Pencil sketches for a children's alphabet book (E-Z)., 170/564; 10 items.
  - Carlson, Viola L. Margaret M. Gate: a Retrospective at Eighty-Five (Tujunga, California, ). **Gage was a dancer, choreographer, teacher, actress and philanthropist who came to Los Angeles in 1940. Includes reminiscences of Mary Wigman and Rabindranath Tagore., 1981; 170/565; Photocopy 116pp.
  - Vacant., 170/566
  - Pomeroy, Everett. 1/2 Snap Shot at Mexico (New Orleans 1900). **Unpublished work illustrated with original photographs, some of which have been hand-coloured., Typescript, 78pp.
  - Reade, Charles. The History of Poor Bob, the Chimney-Sweeper (Cheltenham 1842-1844). **A sequel to Edgeworth's story, illustrated by Reade. Apparently unpublished., 170/568; Manuscript, 35 leaves.
  - Thomson, Virgil (b. 1896). Introductory Solo and Saints' Procession from Four Saints in Three Acts an Opera by Gertrude Stein and Virgil Thomson (Ascain, )., July 1928; *170/569; Manuscript, 5 leaves.
  - Chiba, Toyoji (1881-1944). Memoirs., 170/570; 2 vol.
  - Cox, Palmer (1840-1924). [The Brownies] (New York, ?). **Original pen & ink drawings by Cox of the brownies., ca. 1890; 170/571; 25 items.
  - Henry of Rimini, d. ca. 1314. De quattuor uirtutibus cardinalibus ad ciues Venetos (Germany, )., 1464; 170/572; Manuscript, on paper. 174 leaves.
  - Ristretto delli Stati (s. XVII¹)., 170/573
  - Ludolph of Saxony, 14th century. Expositio super Psalterium (Carthusians of St Barbara, Cologne s. XV¹). **s. XV. Bradfer-Lawrence collection., *170/574; Bound in stamped leather over reused boards.
  - Reinmar von Zweter (s. XIII). Poems [Minnesang] (Germany s. XIII). **Published., *170/575; 2 fragments from a roll, removed from **A1 T365.
    See also: Ferrari, Ferrari Supplement.
  - Anonymous. Diary of a resident near Downey, California. **Daily notes pertaining to farm chores, trips to Downey, Los Angeles, Chapman Ranch, El Monte, etc., ca. 1876-1881; 170/576; 1 vol.
  - James, I.W. [Account book ]. **Includes sketches e.g. San Vicente, lower California, 1888; Pico Oil Company's claim near Newhall Creek, 1891; county road near Newhall., ca. 1877/1891; 170/577; 1 vol.
  - Chesterfield, Philip Dormer Stanhope, 4th earl of (1694-1773). Letter to Bayley (London, ). **Chesterfield says he will purchase a commission as captain for him., June 5, 1753; *170/578
  - Charles II, king of England (1630-1685). An original autograph translation from the Latin by Robert Browning of the Grant of Arms by His Majesty King Charles II to Colonel William Careloss (England, )., ca. 1900; *170/579; Manuscript, 15 leaves.
  - Renouard, Antoine Augustin (1765-1853). Annales de l'imprimerie des Alde... Second édition (Paris, )., 1825; 170/580; 3 vol., with holographic annotations by the author.
  - De La Ramée, Louise (1839-1908). Animals of Florence [and] The New Danger., *170/581; Manuscript, 37pp.
  - Hobart, L.C. Original Sketches for The Ore-Seeker., 1860; *170/582; 29 leaves.
  - Varia medica (S. Italy, s. XIII¹)., 170/583; Manuscript, 51 leaves.
  - Ludolph de Suchen, Voyages to the East (Bavaria s. XV ex.). **Belonged to the Benedictines of St Sebastian, Ebersberg., 170/584; Manuscript, on paper. 96 leaves.
  - Anfangs und in der Mitte einige sehr wertvolle Volkslieder Auch ein. Mohamed slavische Rarität ersten Ranges (). **A fieldbook of Muslim and Slavonic folksongs and toasts., 1848; 170/585; Manuscript.
  - Gundolf, Friedrich (1880-1931). Gedichte für Elli (Germany, ). **Poems for his wife, Elisabeth., 1914-1920; 170/586; 3 vol.
  - Edgeworth, Lovell. Lectures on Chemistry by Dr. Black and Dr. Hope taken by Lovell Edgeworth in two volumes (Edinburgh 1796). **Half-brother of Maria Edgeworth., 170/587; Manuscript, 989pp.
    The Library only has vol.1.
  - Brooke, Henry. [Journal of a Voyage on the Sailing Ship, Lord Warden, from London to Melbourne, Australia]., October 7, 1873-January 19, 1874; Manuscript, 139pp. **Illustrated throughout by pen and ink sketches.
  - Giovanni da Sulmona. Opera (Sulmona ). **Only surviving copy of this poet's works. Signed and dated by the scribe Antonius Marianicus Sulmontinus. Belonged to the Franciscans of San Niccolo, Sulmona. Bound with other texts, including letter of Janos Hunyadi (d. 1456) to Matthias, Count of Bisterczew, and Prester John, De ritu et moribus Indorum., 1440; 170/589; Manuscript, paper. 105 leaves.
    See also: Rouse.
  - Stearns, Abel (1799-1871). Letters (Los Angeles, ). **Copies of letters on Stearns's cattle and ranching business, real estate holdings in Los Angeles and San Diego counties, taxes, etc., 1861-1864; Manuscript, 480 leaves.
  - Catholic Church. Liturgy and Ritual. Breviary. (Netherlands s. XIV)., 170/591; Fragments.
    ** See Rouse.
  - Poliziano, Angelo (1454-1494). Copy of letter to Piero de' Medici (Italy s. XV)., 170/592; Paper. 2 leaves.
  - Pseudo-Phalaris. Epistolae, transl. Francesco Aretino (Italy, probably Naples, early 1460s)., 170/593; Manuscript, 54 leaves.
  - Anthony of Parma. Sermones (Germany s. XV)., 170/594; Manuscript, 112 leaves.
    **See Rouse.
  - Trattato di Mascalcia (Italy s. XV). **Treatise in Italian on veterinary medicine (horses)., 170/595; Manuscript, paper 99 leaves.
  - Florilegium (Netherlands s. XV). **Rear pastedown: liturgy (s. XII)., 170/596; Manuscript, paper 331 leaves.
  - St Augustine. Florilegium (Germany s. XIV). **Written by Albert de Hamm. Belonged to the Brothers of the Cross, Ostberg., 170/597; A small pocket book in ledger format.
  - Eusebius, et al. (Germany, ). **Belonged to the Carthusians of Busheim., 1476; 170/598; Manuscript, paper 58 leaves.
  - Berkeley, Mary (Cole), countess of (1767-1844). An Address to the Rt Hon. the Peers of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland (London, ). **Marginal notes by the Earl of Malesbury., 1811; 170/599
  - Crocker, J.R. Papers (1812-1816). **Largely concerned with efforts to suppress, on behalf of Mary, Countess of Berkeley, a novel by Thomas Ashe., 170/600; 1 vol.
  - Commonplace Book (England, ). **Poetry and prose selections of many writers in various hands; watercolour illustrations of birds, butterflies, and fruit., ca. 1829-1833; 170/601
  - Bagnall, Lucy Elizabeth (Sherwood) (1808-1835). Album (England, ). **Watercolours, pencil drawings and poems., ca. 1828-1885; 170/602
  - Vacant., 170/603
  - Marsh, Elizabeth née Crisp, Elizabeth. Journal of a Voyage by Sea from Calcutta to Madras, and of a Journal from there back to Dacca; Narrative of her Captivity in Barbary (1756)., December 13, 1774-June 20,1775; 170/604; Manuscript, 65pp.; 112pp.
  - Collings, Jesse (1831-1920). Tour in United States and Canada. **Collins was Under Secretary for the Colonies of the British Administration., 1899; Has no call number: 170/605?; Typescript, 186pp.
  - Bradley, Omar Nelson (b. 1893). The Collected Writings of General Omar N. Bradley. **Speeches, testimony, statements, messages, tributes, interviews, etc., 1945-1975; Has no call number: 170/606?; 6 vol.; photocopies.
  - Bradley, Omar Nelson (b. 1893). Magazine articles by and about General of the Army Omar N. Bradley., 1947-1975; 170/607; 6 vol.; photocopies.
  - Naubert, Christiane Benedicte Eugenie (1756-1819). Alf von Deulman; or, The History of the Emperor Philip and his Daughters. Translated from the German (London, )., 1794; 170/608; 2 vol. **Heavily annotated.
  - Anacreon. The Odes of Anacreon (London, )., 1787; 170/609; **Annotated.
  - Service, Robert William (1874-1958). Plowman of the Moon (Hollywood, California, ). **First draft of work published in 1945., 1944; 170/610; Typescript with holograph corrections.
  - Stoker, Bram (1847-1912). Dracula (New York, ). **Presentation copy to William Winter (), accompanied by letter from Stoker., 1899 November 1899; 170/611
  - Summers, Montague (1880-1948). A Gothic Bibliography. **The author's copy., London, 1941; 170/612; Heavily annotated.
  - Frost, Lowell Chester (b. 1882). Poems of Hua-Lo (Los Angeles: Ward Ritchie, )., 1942; 170/613; **Inscribed and interleaved, with letter from Frost, and Typescript of additional poems.
  - Benassai, Pietro Francesco. Spiegazione e note storiche alla dedica della orazioni di Cicerone (Lucca ). **Phillipps Manuscript no.7204., ca. 1453; *170/614
  - Bado Aureo, Joannes de (John Trevor, d. 1410). De arte heraldica (England, ). **Written by Nicolas Warde; belonged to Thomas Giffard (s. XVI) and Thomas Martin (1697-1791)., 1449; 170/615; Manuscript, on parchment. 29 leaves.
  - Sermones de tempore et de sanctis (Germany s. XV). **Belonged to the Carthusians of Erfurt., 170/616; Manuscript, on paper. 320 leaves.
  - St Augustine. De uita Christiana (Germany s. XV). **Accompanied by Bonaventure's De septem donis Spiritus sancti; Nicholas of Dinkelsbühl's De septem malis. **Belonged to the Benedictines of Liesborn., 170/617; Manuscript paper, 144 leaves.
  - Unidentified Coptic Manuscript., 170/618
  - Armenian Manuscript., 170/619
  - Hildebert of Lemans. Versus de mysterio missae, with gloss (France s. XIII²). **From a manuscript of Hildebert's works not recorded in the standard edition of his Opera. Belonged to the abbey of Billy in Besançon., *170/620; 1 quire.
  - Upton, Nicholas. Liber de militari officio (England, s. XV). **Bound with the proof sheets of Joseph Haslewood's facsimile reprint of The Blasynge of Arms, Wynkyn de Worde, 1496. Belonged to George Townsend, Earl of Leicester (1755-1811); Joseph Haslewood (1760-1833); Sir Thomas Phillipps., *170/621; Manuscript, on parchment and paper. 102 leaves, with heraldic devices coloured.
  - Giunta Publishing House. Stock book (Florence, ). **Inventory of Stock and prices of books for sale., ca. 1600-1610; *170/622; Manuscript, 309 leaves.
  - Nativity play (Italy, s. XIV). Parchment. **Fragment of a roll containing the Annunciation portion of a Nativity play., 170/623
  - Archimedes. Translation by Frederigo Commandino, etc. (Rome 1553-s. XVII med). **Served as the printer's copy for the Aldine edition of Includes Commandino's translation of Archimedes (Rome? /mid s. XVII?). Belonged to the Albani Library., 1558. ca. 1553; *170/624; Manuscript, on paper. 218 leaves.
  - Miller, Henry (1891/1980). Notebook. **Notebook kept by Miller on his cross-country tour of the United States, included are sketches, watercolours, etc., 1940-1941; 170/625; Manuscript, 1 vol.
  - Cusatus, Hieronymus. Fastorum libri XII. (Rome?, ). **Apparently the author's fair copy in his own hand, with numerous corrections on slips of paper neatly pasted in. The work correlates the liturgical calendar with the zodiac., ca. 1525-1535; 170/626; Manuscript, on paper. 230 leaves.
  - Nicolaus di Antonio da Fiesso di Ferrara. Meditationes super passionem Christi; Epistola B.M.V. ad uniuersos Christi fideles (Ferrara s. XV med.). **Humanistic script. Belonged to the Carthusians of St Christopher near Ferrara., 170/627; Manuscript, on parchment. 60 leaves.
  - Mosenthal, Philipp. Lieder (s. XIX). **57 songs with the lyrics in German., 170/628
  - Todd, William A. William A. Todd's Book (Cross River, New York, ). **Collection of American music, without lyrics., 1831; 170/629; Manuscript, 36 leaves.
  - Hours B.M.V. Use of Utrecht (Delft, s. XV). **Written by the Augustinian nuns of St Agnes in Delft. Belonged to Arthur Barry Smith., 170/630; Manuscript, on parchment. 168 leaves.
  - Crowley, Aleister (1875-1947), transl. The Tao Teh King. A new translation by Ko Yuen., 1923; 170/631; Typescript, 89pp. with holograph corrections.
  - Leps, Maurice Edouard (1809-1863). Memoirs (after 1844?). **French naval lieutenant, captain of La Vigie (1841-1844). Memoirs of sea voyages and campaigns (1827-42), including those in the eastern Mediterranean, off the coast of Africa (Senegal), Brazil, Chile and Peru., *170/632; Manuscript, 138 leaves & ca. 30.
  - Seuse (Suso), Heinrich. Horologe de sapience (S.W. France, s. XV ex.). **French translation of 1389 by Jean de Souhabe. Probably belonged to the wife of Francis II de Rochfoucauld., 170/633; Manuscript, on paper. 222 leaves.
  - Aristides, Aelius. Oratio de urbe Roma (Rome?, ). **Translated from Greek by Scipione Forteguerri. Written by Francesco Baroncini., between 1507 and 1513; 170/634; Manuscript, on paper. 18 leaves.
  - St Antoninus of Florence. Summula Confessionis (Fondi, S. Italy, 1478). **Written by Antonio de Capitalibus at the abbey of St Onofrio in Fondi. Apparently copied from a printed edition ()., 1474 or 1477; 170/635; Manuscript, on paper. 140 leaves.
  - Ethiopian manuscripts ** Given by Haile Selassie., *170/636
  - Ketah al-Sahhah fiad-Logha., *170/637
  - Beccadelli, Antonio (1394-1471). Alfonsi regis epistolae [with] legationes et epistolae., 170/638
  - Not described., 170/639
  - Not described., 170/640
  - Farquhar, Francis Peloubet (1887-1974). The Grand Teton, Wyoming: a History of Ascents (San Francisco, )., 1924-1928; 170/641; **Typescript copy.
  - Collectanea. Vitae patrum; L. da Segni, De miseria condicionis humanae; unidentified, incomplete, text; Hugh of St. Victor, Soliloquium de arrha animae; Johannes Herrolt, Sermones (West Germany, 1476-78). **Written by John of Tübingen, subdeacon of the Cistercian abbey of Salem near Heidelberg., 170/642; Manuscript, on paper. 180 leaves. Bound in 15th century deer skin over boards.
  - Alexander de Villa Dei. Doctrinale (Venice?, s. XV). Written by Ludovicus., 170/643; Manuscript, on paper. 37 leaves.
  - Hildenreiner, Anthony (b. 1839). Scrap Book of Proofs of Book Bindings engraved by Hildenreiner, many from Scribner's, Century, Routledge, etc. (New York s.a.). **Book jacket specimens., *170/644; 42 leaves.
  - Ransom, Frederick. Civil War Diary & Sketch Book., 170/645; 1 vol.
  - Papyrus. List of Payments in Greek (s. VI)., 170/646
    Scope and Content
    1 papyrus is the List of Payments Sixth Century A.D.
    7 fragments of papyrus. (Greek?) Gift of Lee Walcott, 2007.
  - Vega, Lope de (1562-1635). La famosa comedia del bien nacido encubierto (s. XVII)., 170/647; Manuscript.
  - Peter of Riga., 170/648
  - Orden general de la Plaza de Mexico., 170/649; 1 vol.
  - Edgeworth, Richard Lovell. Memoirs., 170/650
  - Catholic Church. Lectern service book. Spain s. XVI-XVIII., ***170/651; Parchment. 300 leaves.
    **See Ferrari, p.153.
  - Catholic Church. Lectern Gradual (Spain, ). ** Commissioned by Juan Fernandes de Paredes and Antonia Cornela his wife from Valladolid for the convent of Bernardine nuns of St Mary at Avila., 1539; ***170/652; Parchment 219 leaves.
    See also: Ferrari, p.153.
  - St Athanasius of Alexandria (d. 373). Contra gentiles, De incarnatione Verbi. Latin translation by Ambrogio Traversari (1386-1439); 1 of 5 known manuscripts. Italy s. XV². Bound by Charles Lewis for H. Drury., 170/653; Parchment. 76 leaves.
    ** See Ferrari, p.153.
  - Chalco, Mexico. Collection of original manuscripts... relating to famine, 1741.; 170/654
  - Vacant., 170/655
  - Indulgentie, stationes et mirabilia urbis Rome. Roll. German s. XV¹. Contains prayers to be said at the holy sites., 170/656; Parchment, a roll made up of four sections sewn together.
    ** See Ferrari, pp.153-154.
  - Scroll of Esther., *170/657
  - Manuzio, Paolo (1512-1574). Contract, 1561.; 170/658; 1 leaf.
    ** See M. Lowry, Facing the Responsibility of Paulus Manutius, UCLA Special Collections 1995.
  - Antiphonal. Toledo, Spain, s. XVII ex - XVIII in. Signed and dated by Fr. Johannes Cabello, 1737. Music on five-line staves. Text in a late liturgical gothic script. Four large decorated initials. Bound in full calf over oak boards; 4 brass bosses; painting on front cover of the deposition of Christ dated Toledo 1694. Belonged to the Franciscans of Seville., ***170/659; Parchment. 263pp.
  - Besant, Walter. A Fountain Sealed., 1897; 170/660; Manuscript.
  - Doudney, Sarah (1843-1926). A Romance of Lincoln's Inn., ca. 1893.; *170/661; Manuscript, 23pp.
  - Los Angeles Police Department (). Accompanied by related matter., ca. 1930; *170/662; Scrapbook of clippings.
  - Payn, James (1830-1898). A Country Family., 170/663; Manuscript.
  - A dictionary of philosophical and theological terms in alphabetical order, untitled, Italy, Written by three people., ca. 1400.; 170/664; Paper. 157 leaves. Covers lacking, sewn on 3 split bands.
  - Prayer. Arabic., 170/665; 1 vol.
  - Qur'an. Scribe: Hafiz Muhammad 'Arif ab Sakuni., 1264.; 170/666; 1 vol.
  - Mulla 'Ubaydullah. Persian poem (Du'a')., 170/667; 1 vol.
  - Qur'an (portion: al-Mulk). Surah Yasin 'Amm Al-Fath, al-Wagi'ah E., 170/668; 1 vol.
  - Naokh Ta 'liq, 'Amir 'Ali al-Tabrizi style with poem. Farsi., 170/669; 1 vol. of manuscript fragments.
  - Qur'an (portion: Surat Yasin, al-Fath, al-Wagi 'ah and Tabarak)., 170/670; 1 vol.
  - Qur'an. Fragment in unbound sections. s. X., 170/671
  - Christian prayers. Arabic, s. XVIII?, 170/672
  - Quadragesimale, ca 50 anonymous sermons on the Gospels for Lent and Good Friday. German s. XV med. Written by one person in an uneven hybrid script. Bound in contemporary tawed hide over beveled oak boards. Pastedowns: front, canon law s. XIII, back, grammars. XV., 170/673; Paper. 254 leaves. Quires of 12.
  - Biblical Miscellany. North-East Italy, Includes Genealogia beate Virginis. Liber generationis Ihesu Christi; Alexandre de Ville Dieu, Summarium Biblicum; etc. Written by one person in hybrida and textura scripts., 1370-80.; 170/674; Paper (thick). 20 leaves. Bound in quarter leather over bare beveled oak boards.
  - Centum meditationes passionis domini Ihesu Christi. Latin and German. Cologne, Germany, s. XV med. Written by one person in a well formed hybrida script. Probably belonged to the Carthusians of St Barbara in Cologne to judge from the binding stamps and the saints mentioned. Signature of Pastor Servius Jacobo Rus[...?], s. XVII., 170/675; Parchment. 220 leaves. Bound in contemporary blind stamp calf over wooden boards, single brass fore-edge clasp, back to front.
  - Bede, Commentarius in Cantica Canticorum vol.7.6-7. South Italy, s. XI 3/4. Written in Bari Type Beneventan script. Name (s. XIII): Petro de Caponisso, on leaf. Removed from a printed book: G. Savonarola, Confessionale, Venice, and Matthaeus Corradonus, Speculum confessorum et lumen conscientie, Venice 1535 (UCLA 121963 AMEIP), from the abbey of SS. Flora and Lucilla, O.S.B., Arezzo (Ex libris)., 1524; 170/676; Parchment. 1 leaf.
  - Diurnal. Devotional prayers in Latin and Dutch with Ferial Psalter. The Netherlands (N. Holland) Daily offices of the Temporale and the Sanctorale, without Matins; Ferial Psalter; Common of the Saints., 1450-75.; 170/677; Parchment. 356 leaves.
  - Prayer book in Latin and German, Germany (Goslar?), Portions of two separate prayer books joined together in the early 16th century. Part 1: probably Augustinian house in the diocese of Hildesheim, perhaps in Goslar, to judge from the saints in the first calendar. Note: illumination by the same artists in a manuscript dated 1499 (see H. Tenschert, Lauchtendes Mittelalters 21, 1989, no.49, pp.310-14). Bound in 16th century brown morocco, rebacked, with gilt stamp of Mary in the center of the front and back covers. Ex libris: Frances Paget, cleric (1830); Edward Crawshaw (book label); Sotheby's December 20, 1920, no.105., ca. 1500.; 170/678; Parchment. 70 leaves + 289 leaves.
  - [Shahjahan, Emperor of India.] Muntakhab al-lughab [s. XVIII?]., 170/679; 1 bound vol.
  - Razi, Abu Bakr Muhammad ibn Zakariya, 865?-925? Kitab-i Mansuri., 170/680; 1 vol.
  - [Anonymous prayers to the virgin Mary and to various saints]. (s. XVIII). In Amharic. Gift of Dr. Daniel Solomon, 1982., 170/681; 1 bound vol.
  - Taylor, Z.C. (Zacary Clay), The Rise and Progress of Baptist Missions in Brazil: an Autobiography / by Z.C. Taylor, [Texas: Z.C. Taylor, ]., 1916?; 170/682; 206 leaves. Carbon copy. Bound in mottled boards with buckram(?) spine.
  - Prayer book, Hildesheim. ()., ca. 1500; 170/683; 1 vol.
  - A Trip to the West Indies., 1908; 1 vol. typescript, 69 photographic prints.
  - Book of Hours in Middle Dutch. North-east Netherlands, Written by one person in an angular hybrida., 1475-1500.; 170/685; Paper. 209 leaves. 25 large decorated initials. Bound in calf over oak boards, rebacked.
  - Book of Hours (Use of Utrecht). Arnhem, Brabant, s. XV ex. Written by one person in an upright hybrida script. Bookplate of Gordon H. Craine., 170/686; Paper and parchment. 158 leaves. Colored woodcut of Saint Roch inserted after f. 46. Bound in modern brown calf.
  - Thoma, Richard. Lambda. Contains manuscripts of all his poems except the Promised Land., 1935.; 170/687; 1 vol. with pen and ink drawings and decorations.
  - Office of the Dead. Notated. Italy, Written and signed by presbyter Johannes Jacobus for a religious confraterity founded in 1361. Music on a five-line staff. Text written in a round Italian textura., 1557.; *170/688; Parchment. 32 leaves. Bound in 17th century tooled red calf with heraldic device of Alexander Guidiccioni, bishop of Lucca (1549-1605), rebacked, spine laid down. Old press mark XIX.A.17.
  - Deposition in Latin and Italian. Venice, Between Caterino Rosso and her sons Nicoletus and Tibaldus and her sons by a previous marriage, Ptrus Arbusian and his brother Franciscus, who are accused of having built a wall illegally on her property in the district of San Silvestro causing damage to her well. Heard in Torcello (Venice) before Mattheus Aymo and Antonius Michael and Andreas Marcello (in absentia), judges., May 10, 1392.; ***170/690; Parchment (one skin).
  - Notary's cartulary. Venice, Mestre, Copies of about 60 documents in 2 chronological sequences, the first dating, the second dating from, involving properties of the Gritti family. Written by one person in a well formed notarial cursive script., 1550-60. 1477-1554 1477-1550; 170/691; Parchment. 109 leaves. Bound in 16th century parchment over boards.
  - Book of Hours (Use of Rome). North-East France, s. XV ex. Written by one person in an upright hybrida script. A tiny and attractive pocket prayer book when it was new., 170/692; Parchment. 102 leaves. Bound in dark brown leather over paper boards. Thirteen (7-9 line) initials painted or in gold or on painted or gold grounds.
  - Guibert de Tournai O.F.M., Liber Pharetra. Bologna (?), Italy, s. XIII2/2. Written by one person in a small Italian gothic textura. Two illuminated initials (including f. 128 head of Gregory IX)., 170/693; Parchment. 161 leaves. Bound in 20th century calf over boards in imitation of a medieval binding.
  - Barros, André de (1675-1754). Vida do Apostolico padre Antonio Vieyra. Folio s. XVIII., *170/694; Calligraphic copy.
  - Koran ()., mid-late 19th century; 170/695; Manuscript, 1 vol.
  - Catalogous Neuer Curieuser Buecher de Anno, 1700.; 170/696; Manuscript, on paper. 2 leaves.